Copy Right Reserved by Heaven Forum Produced by sbsl&kite200
很有意思啊!
Lovely!
漂亮的城市.
Beautiful.
你迟到了，喝醉了吧.
You're stoned and you're late.
"numero uno"（意大利著名餐馆）的特点就是 品质优良.
Quality is "numero uno".
这就是所有的货?
Is that everything?
是所有的货?
Is it everything?
所有的货 就是... 你来告诉我.
Everything is... You tell me.
就是你.
Everything is you.
你就是这所有的一切.
You are everything.
汤米, 你就是这一切.
Tommy, you are everything.
今天我看见一个和你长的一样的人...
Today I saw somebody who looked just like you...
你不是在计划耍我吧, 是吗?
You're not planning on singing me through the door, are you?
我这儿有一幅"Corregghio"的作品.
I've got a "Corregghio" in here.
- 你别进来了. - 我他妈进来了!
- You're not coming in. - I fucking am!
不. 因为这画家的名字不是Corregghio, 而是Correggio（意大利画家，帕尔玛画派）.
No. Because it's not a Corregghio, it's Correggio.
就象taco这个词，而不是"tacco"一样.
Just like it's not "tacco", but taco.
不是"paster"而是pasta.
Not "paster" but pasta.
你学到的所有东西都是来自经典轿车杂志
Your entire education comes from Classic Car Magazine.
而且这也不是Correggio的画, 而是一幅Rembrandt（伦勃朗，荷兰画家）的赝品.
And it's not a Correggio, it's a fake Rembrandt.
在你明白以前, 你别和我进去了.
And until you know that, you're not coming in with me.
少跟我来这套, 白痴.
Don't fuck me over here, prat.
别想威胁我, 我可不是菜鸟.
Don't threaten me, I'm not the one wearing an earring.
是谁啊?
Who is this?
我会在那儿等着.
I'll be waiting over there.
是的, 是汤姆 瑞普利.
Yes, it's Tom Ripley.
欢迎. 我一直以来都想见见这个人，他有着...
Welcome. I always wanted to meet the man behind the...
- 各种无耻的传言? - 是声誉.
- Scurrilous rumours? - Reputation.
- 我听说过你很多事情. - 其中有些甚至可能是真实的.
- I've heard so many things. - Some of them may even be true.
- 爽啊. - 这是Guercino（意大利画家）的作品.
- That's fabulous. - It's a Guercino.
太棒了.
Fantastic.
瞧那条线上的力量.
Look at the energy in that line.
The two Parmigianino（意大利画家）.
The two Parmigianino.
很令人惊奇. 稀世珍品啊.
Really stunning. This is eXtremely rare.
好吧.
Okay.
1到2百万美圆. 这是我们谈好的.
1,2 million dollars. That's what we agreed.
- 我们谈好什么了? - 你的合伙人给我打过电话.
- What we agreed? - Your partner called me.
- 李维斯? - 对. - 那小子跟个宠物一样（华而不实）.
- Reeves? - Yes. - More a pet than a partner.
他确实很好说话. 我愿意付900,000.
He was rather persuasive. I wanted to pay 900,000.
既然你已经和他谈过了，我就好好考虑一下
Since you spoke with him I have perused them more carefully.
这幅伦勃朗的赝品一文不值, 但我一个子也不会少给你.
This Rembrandt fake is worthless, but I'm not discounting for that.
不会,因为你会把它作为真迹以80万的价格卖掉, 而Guercino那幅可以卖 40万...
No, because you'll sell it as genuine for 800,000, the Guercino 400,000...
..两幅Parmigianinos的, 也能卖65万.
..the Parmigianinos, 650 for the pair.
加上一些其他的玩意，你能赚3百万美圆.
Add the others and you'll clear 3 million dollars.
- 我要两百万. - 别开玩笑了. 我们谈好了的.
- I want two million. - You must be kidding. We had a deal.
不, 你和李维斯谈好了, 不是和我.
No, you had a deal with Reeves, not with me.
- 130万. - 2百万否则拉倒.
- 1.3. - 2 million or forget it.
不行. 我希望你的人没浪费我的时间.
No. I wish you people wouldn't waste my time.
- 你的人? - 特里, 瑞普利先生走了.
- You people? - Terry, Mr Ripley is leaving.
请不要碰那些东西.
Please don't touch those.
别碰!
Leave them!
特里!
Terry!
- 你杀了他. - 住嘴!
- You've killed him. - Shut up!
- 别杀我. - 住嘴!
- Don't shoot me. - Shut up!
别动! 我们这样交易. 我接受你120万 美圆的出价.
Still! Here's the deal. I'll take your offer, 1.2 million dollars.
不过由于市场的不稳定...
But due to the volatility of the market...
..我会带走几幅画.
..I'll take several of the drawings with me.
- 明白了吗? - 取决于你.
- Is that clear? - It's up to you.
说对了. 所以我可能把这些画全拿走.
That's true. So perhaps I'll take all of them.
想留下折叠夹吗? 是真皮的.
Would you like to keep the folder? It's real leather.
不要跟踪我.
Don't follow me.
很可爱的lcarus（罗马神话一神）.
That is a lovely lcarus.
他飞的离太阳太近了, 不是吗?
He flew too close to the sun, no?
你朋友的事情我很抱歉.
Sorry about your friend.
- 进行的怎么样? - 很顺利.
- How did it go? - Very well.
数清楚120万美圆得花很长的时间.都是你的了.
It takes a long time to count 1.2 million dollars. It's yours.
- 你不想要你的那份了? - 不用了. 交易你说了算.
- You don't want your cut? - No. You made the deal.
- 你的呢? - 因为你我才做成这笔生意.
- What about yours? - I got the deal because of you.
你买了这些画之后,还有40万
After you've paid for the drawings, you'll still have 400,000.
Whoah! 并不是我不相信你...
Whoah! It's not that I don't trust you...
可是我他妈就不相信你.
But I don't fucking trust you.
操!
Fucking hell!
这是瑞普利教授的女子精英学校送来的礼物. 你做的很好.
It's a gift from Professor Ripley's finishing school. You did well.
再见. 你真是一个绅士.
Ciao. You're a gentleman.
你很诚实.
You're an honest man.
再见.
See you.
意大利, 三年之后.
Italy, three years later.
太美了!
Fantastico! It's beautiful!
难以置信的稀世珍品. 我能问问你是花了多少钱才买到的?
An incredibly rare piece. May I ask what you paid?
可以啊. 得花多久才能准备好?
Yes, you can. How long to get it ready?
我们至少需要六个星期时间才可以让 它演奏.
We need at least siX weeks to make it play.
你有13天的时间.
You have 13 days.
这是个惊喜.
It's a surprise.
- 早. - 我把画带来了.
- Morning. - I brought the picture.
很好.多谢.
Good. Thank you.
我和内人请了些客人来喝酒。
My wife and I are having a few people over for drinks.
- 非常欢迎你来. - 你很客气啊.
- You'd be most welcome. - That's very kind.
是过了餐馆左边的第3栋房子 .
It's the third on the left past the restaurant.
也许稍后我们能见到你.
Maybe we'll see you later.
- 很香啊! - 我把房子抵押了去买的这些块菌（调味品）.
- Delicious! - I mortgaged the house to buy these truffles.
- 那么给我们留点. - 我会做点意大利调味饭.
- So leave a little bit for us. - I will make risotto.
- 会让你吃到最好的. - 我相信.
- The best you ever had. - I'm sure.
- 乔纳森在这儿吗? - 他在厨房.
- Is Jonathan here? - He's in the kitchen.
- 你好. - 你认识乔纳森吗?
- Hello. - Do you know Jonathan?
如果我是擅自闯入的话,我会想想我是否 可能在其他地方.
I'd like to think if I were gate crashing, I'd be somewhere else.
- 你见过他的妻子吗? - 没有. - 过来.
- Have you met his wife? - No. - Come.
萨拉, 这是汤姆 瑞普利. 汤姆, 这是萨拉.
Sarah, this is Tom Ripley. Tom, this is Sarah.
- 你好,汤姆.很高兴见到你 -我也是
- Hi, Tom. Nice to meet you. - Nice to meet you.
Amarone（意大利产干红）. 最好的!
Amarone. The best!
- 需要我帮忙吗? - 太需要了.
- May I help? - That'd be great.
- Louisa在哪儿? - 在准备她的Vicenza（意大利城市）的音乐会演出.
- Where's Louisa? - Preparing her concert for Vicenza.
- Louisa Harari,一个极有天赋的大键琴演奏家. - 太棒了!
- Louisa Harari, a very gifted harpsichordist. - How wonderful!
- 你饿了吗? - 不，谢谢.
- Are you hungry? - No, thanks.
但愿我也会弹乐器或是画画，会做任何有创意 的事情.
I wish I could play something or paint or do anything creative.
-谁给你织的毛衣? - 我.
- Who knitted your sweater? - I did.
- 这真是... - 什么?
- That's very... - What?
- 新颖极了. - 妈妈.
- Creative. - Mummy.
- 这是马修. - 你好,马修.
- This is Matthew. - Hello, Matthew.
- 今天是你生日吗? - 不是.
- Is it your birthday? - No.
- 是乔纳森的. - 我知道了.
- It's Jonathan's. - Oh, I see.
你看见过瑞普利住的地方吗?
Have you seen Ripley's place?
他妈的俗不可耐的美国佬! 他弄脏了那个Palladian（意大利建筑家）别墅.
Bloody philistine American! He's ruined that Palladian villa.
暖气修好了，却丢掉了很多内在的 典雅之处
Restored the heat and soul out of it.
那就是和瑞普利打交道的麻烦. 没品位还得花大钱.
That's the trouble with Ripley. Too much money and no taste.
好啊. 你来了. 我们一直在盼你来.
Oh, hi. You're here then. We were hoping you'd come.
- 为什么啊? - 这样的...
- Why? - Well...
让这个夜晚多点乐趣.
To add spice to the evening.
什么意思?
Meaning?
你有一点乡土气息.
You're a bit of a local personality.
那么这意味着?
Meaning?
人们都听说过你.
People have heard about you.
那么?
Meaning?
没什么. 只是...
Nothing. Just...
没什么.
Nothing.
咖啡好了吗?
What happened to the coffee?
马上来.
It's coming.
- 一切还好吧? - 对.
- Is everything okay? - Yeah.
太好了.
Great.
这就是意大利和英国食物的共同点
It's what the ltaliano and English have in common.
很简单. 鸡蛋抹点黄油，亮的一面朝上.
Plain simple food. Eggs in butter, sunny side up.
瑞普利先生! 他自己就拥有一片领地!
Mr Ripley! The lord of the manor himself!
- 真是令人愉快的惊喜! - 过来.
- What a pleasant surprise! - Come here.
你真迷人. 我很想你.
You beautiful man. I've missed you.
你的脸怎么了?
What's the matter with your face?
他不想让你知道他很想见我
He doesn't want you to know he's glad to see me.
瑞普利是个美国佬，但很优雅。 他有教养.
Ripley's a Yank, but a Yank with class. He's got culture.
不止这些.
More than you can say for me.
- 那他见到我会无比兴奋，对吧? - 绝对是.
- But he's overjoyed to see me, eh? - Absolutely.
玛利亚, 你可以回家了.
Maria, you can go home.
不.她可以...给我些鸡蛋 .
No. She can... Some eggs.
我正给她讲一些有关烹调的玩意
I'm just showing her some culinary tips.
- 她是Veneto最好的厨子. - 我相信, 但是鸡蛋的事情不一样!
- She's the best cook in the Veneto. - I bet, but eggs is eggs!
- 我没告诉过你不要靠近我吗 - 是的，你说过.
- Didn't I ask you to never come near me? - Yes, you did.
曾经.
Ever.
但我原谅你, 汤姆.
But I forgive you, Tom.
我相信你不会跟着我, 我的子民?
I trust you were not followed, my liege?
- 我叫她在图书馆放火. - 很有趣!
- I told her to light a fire in the library. - Lovely!
记得那些柏林的画吗? 我卖了40万
Remember those drawings in Berlin? I made 400 grand
而你卖了几百万.
and you made several millions.
你回这儿了.
And here you are.
瑞普利教授的女子精英学校 过的很潇洒啊.
Professor Ripley's finishing school nicely tucked away.
我喜欢.
I like it.
帮个忙.
Please.
谢谢.
Thank you.
你钱花的值.
You spent the money well.
一直都是.
Always.
这儿有很多木材.
There's a lot of wood.
很容易燃起来!
Very flammable!
遭了! 有一点不透油的东西和一块烙铁 就可以成这样.
Oh shit! Bit of greaseproof and a hot iron should do that.
我待会给你找这些东西
I'll sort it out for you later.
"Squisito"（开胃）!
"Squisito"!
我喜欢你的妻子, 她却恨我, 那么她是个 好女人,你很幸运.
I like your wife, she hates me, so she's a good woman, you're lucky.
我不知道我更厌恶那点，你的赞美还是你的嫉妒
I don't know what I dislike more, your admiration or your envy.
- 这不是嫉妒, 我做的一点没问题. - 很好!
- It's not envy, I'm doing all right. - Great!
-我在柏林有3家俱乐部和一家餐馆 - 太好了.
- I've three clubs and a restaurant in Berlin. - Great.
生意很好，而且我不用付一个子的保护费
Business is good and I don't pay one penny for protection.
告诉我你想要什么，要不然某个食客会发现你死在某个 地方
Tell me what you want or a truffling pig will find you dead somewhere
就在1，2个月内.
in a month or two.
我告诉你一些事情, 汤姆.
Let me tell you something, Tom.
我和周围的生意竞争者有些过节
I've got some problem neighbours, business competitors
这需要处理一下. 但我不能被别人认为我涉入其中.
that need deregulating. But I can't be seen to be involved.
柏林的人都认识彼此
Everyone knows everyone in Berlin.
谁死了，谁干的，谁是下一个
Who died, who did it. Who's neXt.
如果我想很干净的处理这些事，我需要一个 与此无关的人帮忙
If I want to play it safe, I need someone who's not connected.
- 你想我去做? - 对.
- And you want me to do it? - Yes.
- 为什么选我? - 总得有人做.
- Why me? - Somebody's got to do it.
一个局外人很重要，但这个人得懂行
An outsider ideally, but someone who knows how to play the game.
即使这个人退休一段时间了
Even somebody who's been on the sidelines for a while.
为什么菜鸟就不行?
Why not someone who's never played?
- 5万对一个菜鸟来说很多了. -无知的代价是昂贵的.
- 50 grand's a lot for an amateur. - lnnocence is eXpensive.
一旦你明白了，小心就得被打发进 监狱里
Once you've digested, avail yourself of one of our lovely local hotels.
你这个傲慢的混蛋. 以前是，以后也不会改变.
You're an arrogant bastard. Always was, always will be.
- 他在这儿干嘛? - 他想要我杀个人.
- Why was he here? - He wants me to kill someone.
- 为什么叫你? - 因为我有能力.
- Why did he ask you? - Because I can.
我知道你行，笨蛋. 你还会缝东西呢.
I know you can, silly. You can sew too.
- 为什么他想杀这个人? - 我猜他不顾一切了.
- Why does he want this person killed? - I assume he's desperate.
他的餐馆很失败，夜总会也快倒闭了
His restaurants are failing, his nightclub's in freefall.
他卷进了一些肮脏的争斗中
He's involved in some squalid turf war.
你不能这样做. 跑到柏林去杀一个人.
You can't do that. Run off to Berlin to assassinate people.
他只是幻想罢了，我不是杀手
He's a fantasist, I'm not as assassin.
- 派对怎么样? - 很爽.
- How was the party? - Smashing.
我知道你不不喜欢.
I knew you'd hate it.
难道他不难过吗?
Isn't it sad about him?
- 谁? - 做画框的那个人. 他得了白血病.
- Who? - The picture framer. He's got leukaemia.
- 自命不凡也是这个病的症状吗? - 不是.
- Is drunken pomposity a symptom? - No.
他只是一个英国人. 他病的不轻，汤姆，他快死了.
He's just English. He's very ill, Tom, he's dying.
真可惜.
It's a shame.
不是吗?
Is it?
李维斯?
Reeves?
我一直在考虑你的问题. 你的天才探索.
I've been reflecting on your problem. Your talent search.
我可能和某个人一起想出来了.
I might have come up with someone.
他就象羔羊一样纯真
He's as innocent as a newborn lamb.
我认为在那些天真无邪的外衣下，他也许能行
I think under all that soft, white fleece, he might be capable.
- 乔纳森 Trevanny. - 我叫 Peter Wister.
- Jonathan Trevanny. - My name's Peter Wister.
我为欧洲的一家刺杀领导人的组织工作
I work for a European head-hunting agency.
我们提供非常诱人的短期合同.
We offer highly lucrative short-term contracts.
我非常抱歉, 你弄错了.我是个...
I'm terribly sorry, you've made a mistake. I'm a...
我是个给画制边框的人. 我有一家小店.
I'm a picture framer. I have a small shop.
- 不. 没弄错. 我可以保证就是你. - 你怎么知道我的名字?
- No. No mistake. I can assure you. - How did you get my name?
明天中午12点我们能在Cipriani喝杯咖啡吗?
Can we meet for coffee at the Cipriani about twelve noon?
我向你保证这会让你发一笔大财.
I promise you it will be to your considerable financial advantage.
有组织的犯罪毁掉了太多无辜者的生活
Organized crime wrecks the lives of millions of innocent people
我们必须为此做点什么.
and we need to do something about it.
- 你到底在干些什么? - 这项工作要花两天的时间.
- What eXactly are you after? - The job will take two days.
到时我们付你5万.
Then we pay you 50 grand.
- 多少? - 50,000美圆. 保证了的.
- How much? - 50,000 dollars. Guaranteed.
就两天? 什么工作?
For two days? What's the work?
杀一个绝世恶人.
To kill an eXtremely evil man.
杀人？什么？
To kill? What?
这绝对没有危险.
There's absolutely no risk.
等等, 这是个玩笑吧.
Wait a minute, this is some sort of a joke.
你觉得我他妈给你开玩笑? 这不是"Candid Camera"（用来偷拍的袖珍照相机，喻指好玩）.
You think this is a fuckin' joke? This ain't "Candid Camera".
我一直在跟你说实话. 一个他妈的玩笑!
I'm being straight with you. A fucking joke!
不好意思. 但是你确实找错人了.
I'm sorry. But you've definitely got the wrong person.
- 我不那么认为. - 你从哪知道我的名字的?
- I don't think so. - Where did you get my name?
我们查了查.
We done a search.
如果这不是个玩笑，那么是误会 请忘记你见过我
If this isn't a joke, it's a mistake. Please forget you ever met me
我保证我不会跟任何人说。好吗?
and I promise I won't say anything about this to anyone. All right?
50,000 美圆是一大笔钱. 你有一个漂亮的儿子.
50,000 dollars is a lot of money. You have a beautiful son.
而你因为慢性骨髓白血病快他妈死了.
And you're fuckin' dying of chronic myeloid leukaemia.
- 什么? - 我刚才说过.
- What? - It's like I said before.
我们做了些调查.
We do our homework.
如果你改变主意了,我会在这儿呆几天.
If you change your mind, I'll be here for a couple of days.
- 你好. - 汤姆，他是个小人.
- Hello. - Tom, he's a wanker.
你想要一个菜鸟, 他们一起来了.
You wanted an innocent, they come together.
- 那么他会去干? - 当然.
- So he's going to deliver? - Of course.
- 你给他开的什么价? - 50,000 美圆对小人的价.
- What did you offer him? - 50,000 dollars like a wanker.
- 把价钱加倍. 差额我来付. - 你有50,000美圆 ?
- Double it. I'll pay the difference. - You have 50,000 dollars?
你还好吧?
Are you okay?
- 你脸色很不好. - 只是有一点不安.
- You look pale. - Just a bit shaky.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
我遇见一个从没见过的人，他知道我有 白血病.
I bumped into a total stranger who knew I had leukaemia.
- 全世界都知道. - 这是个小镇.
- The whole world knows. - It's a small town.
我在知道.
Yes, I know.
- 你不应该感到羞耻. - 我没有说我这样认为.
- You shouldn't be ashamed of it. - I didn't say I was.
别太为难自己了.
Don't be so hard on yourself.
- 天啊，我很抱歉. - 没什么.
- Oh God, I'm sorry. - It's okay.
没什么.
It's okay.
- 我吓着了. - 我知道.
- I'm scared. - I know.
我只是希望一切都有所改变
I just wish everything were different.
我希望你没接那份工作.
I wish you didn't have that job.
我们需要钱.
We need the money.
听我说... 求你了.
Look... please.
-我很抱歉让你心烦了. - 那就走开.
- I apologize for upsetting you. - Then please leave.
当你来柏林的时候，我可以带你去见一个 权威的专家
When you come to Berlin, I can get you to see a top specialist,
绝对没有任何的问题!
absolutely no obligation!
我不需要另一个医师的意见!
I don't need another second opinion!
我这辈子已经有两次大夫说我快死了 但我还活着
Twice in my life doctors have said I was dying. But I'm still here.
看着我.
Look at me.
我还在这儿活着.
I'm still here.
我已经被授权在原来的价码基础上增加你的佣金.
I've been authorized to increase the original offer.
100,000 美圆.
100,000 dollars.
听我说... 我很抱歉.
Look... I'm sorry.
谢谢你的时间. 给我打电话.
Thank you very much for your time. Please call me.
- 你好。我能载你一程吗? - 不用了，多谢.
- Hi. Can I give you a ride? - No, thanks.
- 我来开车. - 我喜欢走路.
- I'll drive. - I like to walk.
不给我面子啊.
Indulge me.
- 多谢你的派对. 你好吗? - 好啊.
- Thanks for the party. How are you? - Fine.
这与我无关, 但我知道你不是.
It's none of my business, but I know you're not.
我相信谈这个不可能轻松.
I'm sure it can't be easy to talk about it.
是的,事实上不轻松.
No, it's not as a matter of fact.
- 我刚才确实想说... - 谢了。没有什么可说的了.
- I did just want to say... - Thanks. There's not much to say.
- 你看了专家吗? - 对。Gianni大夫.
- Do you have a specialist? - Yes. Dr Gianni.
- 他在哪儿? - 这儿.
- Where is he? - Here.
- 在这儿的诊所? - 对.
- Here in the clinic? - Yes.
我知道了.
Oh, I see.
- 他们是一个能胜任的团队. - 我相信.
- They're a competent team. - I'm sure.
- 他是个漂亮的小男孩. - 谢谢.
- He's a beautiful little boy. - Thank you.
如果我有一个这样的孩子, 我会为他做任何事. 无论什么.
If I had a little boy like that, I'd do anything for him. Anything.
- 这正是我努力去做的. - 我相信.
- It's what I'm trying to do. - I'm sure you are.
- 多谢搭车. - 没什么.
- Thanks for the lift. - Cheers.
那晚我没意识到场合不对
I didn't realise the occasion the other night.
生日快乐。它们是一堆杂交的植物. 谁知道会成什么样
Happy birthday. They're a miXture. Who knows what will come up.
那就是种植的魅力所在.
That's the beauty of planting things.
谢谢.
Thank you.
小心点.
Take care.
我在想诊所里某个人给我说的话.
I've been thinking of something someone at the clinic said to me.
也许我会去见见这个人.
I might go and see this man.
我觉得你应该去.
I think you should.
爸爸，你会永远离开我吗?
Daddy, are you going away for ever?
- 不是的. - 但妈妈说你会的.
- Not quite yet. - But Mummy said you will.
妈妈也许说的对. 但不是这次.
Mummies may be right. But not this time.
都干完了吗?
All finished?
"关门至周一"
"Closed until Monday"
- 乔纳森离开很久了吗? - 不长时间.
- Is Jonathan away for long? - No, not long.
- 你说他到什么地方去了? - 柏林.
- Where did you say he'd gone? - To Berlin.
我不知道你...
I don't know how much you...
喝了...多少?
How much l... drink?
喝翻了? 酒醒了吗?
Bathe? Work out?
- 你对他的情况知道多少? - 不知道，我一无所知.
- How much you know of his condition? - Nothing, I'm an innocent.
他有慢性脊髓白血病.
He has chronic myeloid leukaemia.
天啊，我很抱歉.
My God, I'm so sorry.
谢谢了。这让他有机会得到其他的 诊断意见
Thank you. This opportunity for him to get a second opinion
有这个研究基金会.
came up at this research foundation.
他没说过这个, 但是我知道他很生气.
He doesn't talk about it, but I know he's angry.
因为他可能很快就死了，而我们还会活着
He's angry because he'll probably die soon, while we go on living.
他很生气还这么年轻.
He's angry to be so young.
他很生气他可能看不到马修长大了
He's angry that he might not see Matthew grow up.
你呢? 你生气吗?
And you? Are you angry?
有的时候. 我是那么的爱他，但...
Sometimes. I love him completely but...
当这一切结束了我的一部分会感到开心.
there's a part of me that will be glad when it's all over with.
而这说出来是非常恐怖的.
And that's a terrible thing to say.
我认为你不能说一些很恐怖的事情出来的。 甚至你想都不会去想.
I don't think you could even say anything that terrible. Or think it.
你的感受一点也不恐怖.
What you feel isn't terrible at all.
乔纳森很幸运能够有你，我想象的出他知道这点.
Jonathan is fortunate to have someone like you, and I imagine he knows it.
- 怎么样了? - 检查? 很彻底.
- How was it? - The eXam? Thorough.
- 什么时候拿到结果? - 早上.
- When do you get the results? - In the morning.
Wentzel大夫是最好的. 我并不喜欢大夫.
Dr Wentzel's one of the best. I don't like doctors myself.
这就是我们要做的. 早上去拿检查结果,
This is what we're going to do. Get your results in the morning,
再告诉我你要什么.
then you can tell me what you want.
A: 我可以开车送你到机场.
A: I can drive you to the airport.
或者B: 我们可以做另外的事情.
Or B: we can do the other thing.
另外的一件事情.
The other thing.
是的.
Yeah.
9点在这儿见我.
Meet me here at 9 o'clock.
那时你就可以带着10万美圆坐飞机回家了.
Then you can get a plane home 100 grand richer.
由你自己决定. 明天见.
It's your decision. I'll see you tomorrow.
那么? 你的晚会怎么样?
So? How was your evening?
还有点趣味.
Not without interest.
- 你是如何表演的? - 用耳朵.
- And how did you play it? - By ear.
希望是这样.
Well I hope.
一段优美的...
A nice...
稳定的旋律?
steady rhythm?
整个表演并不是我一人完成的.
I didn't play the whole piece.
不是.
No.
为什么不是?
Why not?
把身子转过去我再告诉你.
Turn over and I'll tell you.
不行! 我现在就想知道.
No way! I want to know now.
把身子转过去我再告诉你.
Turn over and I'll tell you.
那她是不是太容易了?
Was she too easy?
把身子转过去我再告诉你.
Turn over and I'll tell you.
现在告诉我.
Now tell me.
我有你的检查结果。这没有什么新鲜的东西.
I have your test results. They don't appear to tell us anything new.
在骨髓移植手术后，你进入了一个部分复圆期.
After the bone marrow transplant, you went into a partial remission.
之后转入慢性阶段.
And then lapsed to the chronic phase.
最新的检查只能表明一些我认为你已经知道 的东西.
These latest tests only show what I think you already know.
你的情况依然很严重. 因此...
Your situation remains grave. So...
..你想要我给你什么?
..what do you want of me?
- 一个可预见的将来. - 我无法给你这个.
- A future. - I can't give you that.
我恐怕这不是我能力可达到的.
It is, I fear, not in my brief.
- 你会在柏林呆多久? - 不长.
- How long will you stay in Berlin? - Not long.
- 祝你好运. - 我也许需要.
- I wish you luck. - I may need it.
- 你给了我多少? - 预付50000，事成后再给50000.
- How much have you given me? - 50 grand up front, 50 grand later.
如果你不是这么的有礼貌, 你会数数的.
If you weren't so polite, you'd count it.
- 那么你这样用这个东西? - 你把那个旋进枪管.
- So how do you use this thing? - You screw that into the barrel.
- 什么, 象这样... - 对, 只需要旋进去.
- What, like this... - Yes, just screw it.
- 我射他哪个部位? - 只要瞄准他然后开枪.
- And where do I shoot him? - Just point it and pull the trigger.
是他. 他就通常戴那些恐怖的金边眼镜
It's him. He usually wears those horrible gold-rimmed glasses
还有特大的俄国皮帽子. 他们杀了3头熊来做这些帽子.
and a great big Russian furry hat. They killed three bears for that.
他叫Leopold Belinsky, 一个傻逼俄国佬.
His name is Leopold Belinsky, a fucking Russian.
他一年前离开的莫斯科.
He left Moscow a year ago.
在他的俱乐部经营妓女和毒品
Running prostitutes and drugs out of his clubs.
他手下的妓女年龄越来越小 毒品纯度越来越高.
The prostitutes keep getting younger and the drugs keep getting harder.
这个混蛋是一个十足的疯子 .
This scumbag is totally out of order.
你摆平了他，正派人会把你他妈看作圣人.
You take him out and decent people will call you a fucking saint.
他每周都会到动物园一次, 象钟表一样的有规律,
Once a week, regular as clockwork, he visits the zoo.
他总是会最后去昆虫馆, 那儿都是他的朋友:
He always ends up in the insect room, where his real friends are:
虱子, 爬虫, 就象他一样肮脏的玩意.
bugs, creepy crawlies, slimy things just like himself.
你会在那儿找到他.
That's where you'll find him.
那个时间不会有其他人在那儿.
There's no one else there at that time.
孩子们都在学校.
Kids are all at school.
- 抱歉，先生. - 我只是来拿我的东西.
- EXcuse me, sir. - I just came to get my things.
不，别走. 我正要走.
No, stay. I'm just going.
喂?
Hello?
嗨，汤米! 猜猜怎么着.
Hi, Tommy! Guess what.
你所谓的小人, 他做了那桩买卖.
Your wanker, he did the business.
乔纳森?
Jonathan?
你好啊.
Hello.
- 早上起我就在等你了. - 现在就是早上了.
- I eXpected you in the morning. - It is morning.
回家真是太好了.
It's so great to be back.
真美.
It's beautiful.
我们负担不起这个.
We can't afford this.
那么他说了什么?
So what did he say?
- 谁说了什么? - 那个专家.
- What did who say? - The specialist.
哦，他...
Oh, him...
是的... 他说...
Well... he said...
没什么不一样的.
Nothing's changed.
没有比这更糟的了!
It's no worse!
嗨!
Hello!
- 你好吗? - 很好，多谢了. 你呢?
- How are you? - Very well, thanks. You?
我在楼下的化装间找到一些有用的东西.
I've found something to go in the downstairs powder room.
- 萨拉说你找我. - 是啊，我们想你.
- Sarah said you called round. - Yeah, we missed you.
- 你去柏林了. - 是的.
- You went to Berlin. - Yeah.
- 一举多得的旅行? - 很有意思.
- Productive trip? - lnteresting.
你拿这些来做什么? 做 走廊?
What do you make of these? For a hallway?
太好了!
Nice!
- 很好! - 我同意.
- Very nice! - I thought so.
马修，你弄完了吗? 我得准备工作了.
Matthew, have you finished? I have to get ready for work.
个大的孩子都吃谷类食品.
Big boys eat their cereal.
- 好吧. - 那是谁啊?
- Okay. - Who was that?
- 打错了. - 又错了?
- Wrong number. - Again?
不, 不. 再多点.
No, no. More.
做的怎么样了? 不, 多点.
How are you doing? No, more.
- 想吃点东西吗? - 不, 谢了. - 多来点!
- Want something to eat? - No, thanks. - More!
觉得怎么样?
How do you feel?
- 我想要的只是你欠我的. - 这真他妈爽呆了!
- All I want is what you owe me. - This is fucking fantastic!
可以给我欠我那些钱吗?
Please may I have the rest of my money?
- 谢了. - 还想要点吗?
- Thank you. - Want some more?
- 要点什么? - 你想象的东西.
- More what? - More of what you fancy.
你可以把钱变成任何东西.
You can turn money into all sorts.
听着，我不能...
Listen, I couldn't...
我所做的，我不会... 我不能再做了.
What I did, I wouldn't... I couldn't do it again.
很遗憾!还有50000在等着你 ... 比以前容易多了.
Shame! There's another 50 grand... And so much easier.
我宁愿我没有再遇见你.
I'd rather we didn't meet again.
在这种情况下,工作做了一半就会有麻烦.
In matters like this, the trouble starts when the job is half done.
即使混蛋也有朋友，即使死了的混蛋.
Even bastards have friends. Even dead bastards.
- 你在说什么? - 在没把事情弄清楚以前...
- What are you talking about? - You can't shoot people...
..你不能就这么杀一个人. 如果你看重你的生活你就不会这样.
..without tidying things up. Not if you value your life.
我的生活?
My life?
如果我是你我不会参加任何的家庭野餐.
I wouldn't go on any family picnics if I was you.
- 你去哪儿了? - 我把车开到修车库去了 .
- Where were you? - I took the car to the garage.
但它不值得去修理了.
But it isn't worth repairing.
很好.
Great.
那么我们该怎么办?
So what do we do?
我们... 再买辆新的.
We... buy a new one.
- 用什么? - 有些事情...
- With what? - There's something...
..我一直瞒着你. - 我知道.
..I've been keeping from you. - I know.
那个医学研究基金会
This medical research foundation
给了我几千美圆.
gave me a few thousand dollars.
但我必须回去.
But I have to go back.
- 为什么? - 他们在对一种新药...
- What for? - They're doing a clinical trial...
..做临床试验.
..with a new drug.
- 为什么不告诉我? - 我不想你担心.
- Why didn't you tell me? - I didn't want you to worry.
- 因为这很危险? - 不.
- Because it's dangerous? - No.
这可能没什么用. 但至少我们会有一辆新车.
It just might not work. But at least we'd have a car.
因为有风险他们才会给你钱.
They're paying you because there's a risk.
没风险. 而且这不会要很长时间.
There is no risk. And it wouldn't be for long.
不要走. 我们不需要车.
Don't go. We don't need a car.
你好.
Hello.
我要和你谈谈. 到外面来.
I need to talk to you. Outside.
操!
Fuck!
"Scusi". 请继续, 这曲子很美.
"Scusi". Please, it's a beautiful song.
喂。我知道 我待会打给你. 待会!
Hello. I know, I'll call you later. Later!
给你.
Here you are.
这是个套索.
It's a garrotte.
- 我知道这是什么. - 老Belinsky的标志.
- I know what it is. - Signature of old Belinsky.
当他们发现这系在他的生意竞争对手的 脖子上的时候
When they find it round the neck of his business rival,
他们之间会发生战争, 这样我会获利.
it'll start a war between them, then I'll have the field clear.
因此你想让Trevanny用一根牙线在 柏林到杜塞尔多夫的快车上
So you want Trevanny to strangle a Ukrainian Mob boss
扼死一个乌克兰黑帮老大?
on the Berlin to Dusseldorf eXpress with a piece of dental floss?
是的. 或多或少就这样.
Yeah. Well, more or less.
我觉得我们能够说服他.
I think we can talk him into it.
他不会做了.
He's not going to do it.
- 不会? - 他做过一次.
- No? - He did it once.
- 做的很干净利落. - 一次就足够了.
- And very well. - Once is enough.
我不会再让他做了.
I won't let him.
- 不? - 不了, 游戏结束了.
- No? - No, game over.
结束了. 你他妈是谁啊?
Game over. Who the fuck are you?
这不是游戏, 这他妈是我的下半辈子!
This ain't a game, it's my fuckin' livelihood!
我说了不!
I said no!
好吧.
All right.
喂?
Hello?
"请留言，我会回复."
"Please leave a message, I'll call you back."
你说很容易的.
You said it was easier.
你没说过要勒死人.
You didn't mention strangling anybody.
我想勒死人也勒不死，看看我!
I couldn't strangle anybody even if I wanted to. Look at me!
这可不是有没有蛮力的问题.
It's not a matter of brute strength.
在适当的地方施加适当的力量，那就成了.
You apply the right pressure to the right point. You can do it.
乔纳森... 哦，妈的!
Jonathan... Oh, fuck!
他妈的，他在哪儿?
Where the fuck is he?
妈的!
Fuck!
动手啊.
Just fucking do it.
要不你的家人会死在你面前.
Otherwise your family's going to die before you do.
别耍我!
Don't fuck with me!
他们来了.
They're coming.
他每周两次坐这趟车出差.
He takes the train twice a week for business.
他前列腺有问题，所以一半的时间都呆在厕所里.
He has prostate problems so he spends half the trip in the toilet.
你有万能钥匙，就在那里干掉他.
You have a master key to it. That's where you'll do him.
你有套索，也有枪，但...
You've got a garrotte but you've also got a gun. But...
听我说，这很重要.
This is very important, listen to me. It's very important.
你必须用套索.
You have to use the garrotte.
我们乐观一点，不需要那个.
Let's be optimistic and say we won't need that.
把套索给我.
The noose, please.
别走远，我要你帮忙.
Stick around, I'll need your help.
他回来了吗!
Has he come back yet? Jesus!
这是无烟车厢，真无礼!
This is a non-smoking car. How rude!
如果他没很快回来， 我们就要等到过了杜塞尔多夫，我可不想这样.
If he doesn't come back soon, we have to wait till after Dusseldorf.
看好我的表，如果弄坏了，我就杀光车上所有人.
Keep my watch. If it breaks, I'll kill everyone on this train.
我会把他弄到里面，你在外面等着,
I'm going to take him inside. You wait outside,
说你妻子在里面，病的不轻.
say your wife is in there very ill.
到走廊去，他过来的时候， 你就转过身看着我.
Go into the corridor. When he comes toward you, turn and look at me.
你穿过这些门，然后停在这儿.
Wait right through these doors and stop there.
不管他做什么，我来处理剩下的事.
I'll take care of the rest.
抱歉，我夫人在里面，她不舒服.
I'm sorry... my wife's in there, she's being sick.
Guleghin先生? 你没事吗?
Mr Guleghin? Is everything all right?
汤姆!
Tom!
- 他死了吗? - 我不知道.
- Jesus! Is he dead? - I don't know.
把他腿拖进来.
Get his legs in.
汤姆! 另一个家伙过来了.
Tom! The other guy's coming now.
- 真的? - 真的.
- Are you sure? - Yes.
抱歉，我不会说德语，我在等着.
Sorry, I don't speak German. I'm waiting.
Guleghin先生, 你在吗?
Mr Guleghin, are you in there?
头等车厢从来没这么拥挤过.
It never used to be so crowded in first-class.
我能来点吗?
Can I have some more?
我不想催你，但去米兰的飞机一小时后起飞.
I don't want to rush you, but the flight to Milan leaves in an hour.
我还有20多分钟
Please, I've had over 20 minutes
来变成全欧洲杀手最想杀的人了.
to adjust to becoming one of Europe's most wanted.
我呕吐，颤抖，如此不正常
I know I must look ludicrous to you with my heaving, and shaking
我知道你一定觉得很可笑
and my shockingly awful normalness.
我希望你能原谅我.
I do hope that you will forgive me.
我不能面对我儿子! 我不能面对我儿子!
I can't look at my son! I can't look at my son!
我无法解释我是如何挣到10万美元的.
I can't eXplain how I made 100,000 dollars.
我真的很害怕我有病. 我不舒服...
And I really fear I am in fact ill. I'm not well...
我是移民局的.
I'm from the lmmigration Authority.
你能出去吗?
Could you go outside, please?
- 好的. - 谢谢.
- All right. - Thanks.
我该谢谢你，如果你没帮我，我一定活不了.
I should thank you, I wouldn't be alive if you hadn't helped me.
但我不能说谢谢你.
But I can't say thank you.
我对你一无所知.
I don't know anything about you.
你是什么人?
Who are you?
我是一件艺术品，一个天才的即兴表演家. 我不像你那么有良知
I'm a creation. A gifted improvisor. I lack your conscience.
我年轻的时候，那让我很苦恼， 现在不了.
When I was young that troubled me. It no longer does.
我不担心被捉到，也不相信有人在盯着我.
I don't worry about being caught as I don't believe anyone is watching.
不会因为那些人死了，世界就变得更加可悲.
The world is not a poorer place because those people are dead.
路上的车少一辆，就少一点噪音和危险.
It's one less car on the road, a little less noise and menace.
你今天很勇敢，你为你的家庭放弃了金钱.
You were brave today. You put some money away for your family.
就这些.
That's all.
如果你没有良知，你为什么要帮助我?
If you lack my conscience, then why did you help me on the train?
我不知道，但我一点都不奇怪.
I don't know, but it doesn't surprise me.
我只知道每天不停有人出生.
The one thing I know is that we're constantly being born.
为什么是我?
But why me?
为什么要挑我?
Why did you pick me?
有几分是因为你行. 还有几分是因为你侮辱了我.
Partly because you could. Partly because you insulted me.
但最重要的是因为没有选择.
But mostly because that's the game.
我们必须去赶飞机了，走吧?
We have to get this flight. Shall we?
怎么了?
What's going on?
这是哪里来的?
Where did this come from?
- 你不会相信的. - 说说看.
- You... you wouldn't believe me. - Try me.
- 嬴来的. - 嬴的?
- I won it. - You won it?
是的，轮盘赌.
Yes, roulette.
你什么时候开始玩那玩意的?
Since when did you play roulette?
- 在柏林. - 别骗我.
- In Berlin. - Don't lie to me.
Wentzel医生带我们去了赌场...
Dr Wentzel took us to a casino...
- 难道那也是治疗方法之一? - 我们嬴了几千马克...
- Is that some kind of therapy? - We had a few thousand marks...
- 是真的. - 你发了一笔小财...
- It's true. - You won a small fortune...
..决定藏起来. - 我想给你个惊喜.
..and decided to hide it. - I wanted it to be a surprise.
你和汤姆 瑞普利一起干了什么?
What were you doing with Tom Ripley?
我在机场遇到他.
I met him at the airport.
他让我搭车.
He offered to give me a lift.
Wentzel医生有一个好方法.
Dr Wentzel has this system.
你下红的注，如果你输了...
You bet on the red and if you lose...
不管你们做什么，别对我说谎!
Don't lie to me, whatever it is you're doing!
- 你不信我? - 不.
- You don't believe me? - No.
我和医生说了一大堆废话,
I go through all that eXhausting crap with doctors,
是想寻找希望.
hoping against hope, looking for some glimmer.
接着，我生平第一次
Then I get an incredible stroke of luck
遇上了好运,
for the first time in my life,
你却指责我说话，指责我说谎!
and then you accuse me of lying to you. You accuse me of lying!
听着! 我有钱了.
Look! I have some money.
给你，给我，给马修.
Money for you and for me and for Matthew.
钱是最重要的，是吗?
And money is what's important, isn't it? Isn't it?
- 哪儿找到了? - 在比萨郊区的一个鸡窝.
- Where did you find it? - In a chicken coop, outside Pisa.
他们重新弄了琴腿，去掉了外面的感光剂..
They completely rebuilt the legs and stripped all the emulsion off.
我不能...
I can't...
我还不能，让我平静一下.
I just can't. Give me a moment.
停!
Stop it!
别在碰了，她太珍贵了.
Never touch her again. She's too good for you.
我知道.
I know.
- 怎么了? - 他们中还有一个活着.
- What's wrong? - One of them's still alive.
- 你怎么知道的? - 我在世界新闻上听到的.
- How do you know? - I heard it on the World News.
天，我还以为你只听网上广播呢.
Jesus! I always figured you for a Talk Radio man.
我想我勒他的劲不够.
I guess I didn't strangle him long enough.
用手勒总比不上套索套.
It's not likely a garrotte comes with a manual.
有一个人把我看得很清楚.
One of them got a very good look at me.
第一条规则，别为你不能控制的事情担心.
The first rule is don't ever worry about anything you can't control.
我想他们不会跟到这里的 如果他们来了，我会告诉你的.
I don't think they can trace us here. And if they do, I'll let you know.
我的家里人怎么办，我很担心他们.
What about my family? I'm just worried about my family.
如果他们要找谁算帐，他们会找我.
If they come for anyone, they'll come for me.
那些巴尔干人会以牙还牙的.
These Balkan types tend to take strangling quite personally.
妈的，他不是李维斯!
Shit, it's not Reeves!
他在哪儿?
Where is he?
刚才在这儿.
He was here.
这里还有个出口.
There's another eXit.
你去追他.
You get him.
别杀了他.
Let the man live.
我们乘此机会向
Let us take this time to pay a well-deserved homage
汤姆 瑞普利表示我们长久以来的敬意
to the ever and ever rising souffle' of Tom Ripley.
看啊.
Look at that.
- 你真是个好主妇. - 当然.
- You are the perfect housewife. - That's true.
我该嫁给你.
I should marry you.
我来.
It's okay, leave it.
今天已经有三个打错的电话了.
I already had three wrong calls today.
喂?
Oh yeah?
Hello?
李维斯!
Reeves!
多久...
Yeah? How long...
哦，上帝!
Oh, my!
你在这里干什么?
- Come on. - What are you doing here?
别翻浑了, 汤姆.
Don't get arsey, Tom.
他们知道你在柏林了?
So they located you in Berlin?
- 我不知道他们怎么发现的. - 你把他们领到我家了.
- I don't know how they found out. - Now you lead them to my house.
现在可有些对你不利的消息啊， 说你完蛋了.
There's something of the mudslide about you. You bring everything down.
去你妈的!
Fuck you!
- 你让我进来吗? - 让你进来？不，我不这么认为.
- Are you gonna let me in? - Let you in? No, I don't think so.
- 你又单枪匹马了. - 你这杂种.
- You're on your own again. - You bastard.
狗娘养的杂种!
You fucking bastard!
我会带他们来找你, 狗娘养的杂种!
I'll lead them straight to you, you fucking bastard!
狗娘养的杂种!
You fucking bastard!
去你妈的!
Fuck you!
怎么样? 很棒吗?
How is it? A masterpiece?
玛利亚, 你愿意这个周末去看你姐姐吗?
Maria, would you like to take the weekend to visit your sister?
非常乐意，谢谢.
I would like it very much. Thank you.
宝贝，也许你今天想去维琴查.
My love, maybe you'd like to go to Vicenza today.
你可以在那里的剧院排练，那里声学条件很好.
You can rehearse in the theatre. Such lovely acustics.
好的.
Yeah.
很好.
Fine.
- 那你一个人呆在这儿? - 实际上我在等人呢.
- So you'll stay here by yourself? - Actually I'm eXpecting company.
- 他们会来音乐会吗? - 不.
- Will they come to the concert? - No.
他们不喜欢音乐.
They're not music lovers.
- 你来吗? - 当然.
- Will I see you there? - Absolutely.
我要你销毁所有的有我名字或电话的东西
I want you to get rid of anything that might have my name
李维斯的也一样.
or phone number on it. And do the same with Reeves.
怎么?有麻烦了?
Why? Are we in trouble?
是的，别打电话给我，也别来我这儿.
Yes. Don't phone me and don't come to the house.
- 如果你有麻烦，我可以帮你. - 你别管，那样才安全.
- If you're in trouble, I'll help. - Stay away. Stay safe.
学校很好吗?
Did you have a nice day in school?
我要出门几天.
I've got to go away for a few days.
有些生意上的事要解决.
I have some business to settle.
我有些事情要处理一下...
I want to fiX up something for after I've...
我现在还不想说.
I don't want to go into it yet.
什么事?你不认为我们该谈谈吗？
What thing? Don't you think we should talk about it?
是的，过几天我回来的时候.
Yes, when I get back, in a couple of days.
和汤姆 瑞普利有关吗?
Is it to do with Tom Ripley?
- 没有. - 乔纳森!
- No. - Jonathan!
我过几天就回来.
I'll be back in a couple of days.
听着，我们该谈谈.
Look, we should talk about this.
- 等我回来再谈. - 很好，再带回来一个装满钱的信封.
- When I get back. - Great! With another fat envelope.
闭嘴!
Shut up!
- 你在这里干什么? - 我想你需要帮助.
- What are you doing here? - I thought you might need help.
回家吧，他们会有很多人的.
Go home. When they come, there might be quite a few of them.
我要留下来.
I'm staying.
- 你怎么对萨拉说的? - 一些谎言.
- What did you tell Sarah? - An assortment of lies.
- 她信吗? - 不信.
- Did she believe any? - I don't think so.
小心.
Watch your step.
- 这是什么? - 机关.
- What are these? - Man traps.
- 喝茶吗? - 好的.
- Would you like some tea? - Yes, please.
- 那些有用吗? - 有用的.
- Do they work? - They work.
是的，我也这么想.
Yeah, I think so.
我们不关门吗?
Shouldn't we close the gates?
不，关也没有用.
No, they'll come in anyway.
我不想这么过.
I don't want to spend my life like this.
- 你害怕了? - 不.
- Are you scared? - No.
我很害怕.
I'm fucking terrified.
来啊.
Come on.
我没想到要问你.
I didn't even think to ask.
以你现在的状况，你能吃肉吗?
With your condition, can you eat meat?
- 是的，我不是很饿. - 你该吃点东西.
- Yes, I'm just not very hungry. - You should eat something.
你的力气会用的上的，肉很好.
You may need your strength. The meat is fantastic.
是战争纪念碑那边的小屠户铺的.
It's from the little butcher's just by the war memorial.
我的厨娘玛利亚一度和那屠户关系亲密.
Our cook Maria was once quite intimate with the butcher.
她弄了些好肉.
She got some very nice cuts.
- 你认为我们会逃脱吗? - 为什么不?
- Think we'll get away with it? - Why not?
我总是能化险为夷.
I'm not the sort of person to get away with things.
学校里其他孩子都能逃脱,
At school other kids did,
我不能，总被抓到.
but not me, I always got caught.
你被抓到是因为，你没想到要杀了你的老师.
You got caught because you didn't think of just killing your teachers.
我真受不了这样等待.
I can't stand this waiting.
我小时候做在板凳上一等就是几个小时
When I was a little boy I waited on the beach for hours
等我的父母做船回来，他们淹死了.
for my parents to come back from a boat ride. They drowned.
我能永远等下去.
I could wait for ever.
喂?
Hello?
汤姆, 我是萨拉. 乔纳森在吗?
Tom, this is Sarah. Is Jonathan there?
- 不，为什么? - 你知道他在哪儿吗?
- No. Why? - Do you know where he is?
我为什么该知道?
Why should l?
- 因为，我认为，你知道. - 抱歉，我不懂.
- Because I think you do. - Sorry, I don't understand.
- 我知道有事情. - 别担心.
- There's something going on. - I wouldn't worry.
- 别对我说别担心. - 我能过会儿给你打回去吗?
- Don't tell me not to worry. - Can I call you back?
不，别挂.
No, don't hang up.
我现在有事情，我要打几个电话，然后给你回话.
I'm just in the middle of something. I'll make some calls and ring back.
- 等一下! - 再见.
- Please wait! - Bye.
妈的!
Fuck!
永远别给朋友经济上的建议.
Never give financial advice to friends.
如果他们抓到李维斯怎么办?
What if they catch Reeves?
他们永远也抓不到李维斯. 很不幸.
They'll never catch Reeves. Unfortunately.
他会告诉他们我的事，是吗?
He'd tell them about me, wouldn't he?
也许，但他现在已经在南美了
Probably. But he's already in South America
正在逼那个可怜的医生在给他做整形手术呢.
making life miserable for some unfortunate plastic surgeon.
看他在不在.
Check if he's there.
抱歉，这是你的早餐.
Sorry. It's your breakfast.
- 他们没来? - 还没.
- They didn't come? - Not yet.
呆在这儿.
Stay in here.
别动，别出声.
Keep still! Keep your mouth shut.
- 我叫你呆在里面. - 他死了吗?
- I told you to stay inside. - Is he dead?
我不知道，我又不是专家.
I don't know and as we know, I'm no eXpert.
上帝，是被我打中的那个人!
Jesus Christ! It's the guy I shot!
你不该再活过来!
You should have stayed dead the first time!
- 闭嘴! - 你要我帮你解开吗?
- Shut up! - Do you want it off?
我希望他别流血了.
I wish he'd stop bleeding.
你有手机吗?
Do you have a portable phone?
- 是的. - 在身上还是车里?
- Yes. - On you or in the car?
- 在我口袋里. - 拿出来.
- It's in my pocket. - Get it out.
打电话给派你来的人，告诉他你看清楚了,
Call the man who sent you here and tell him you got a good look,
我们不是车上的那些人.
and we were not the people on the train.
如果你让他相信了
If you do that convincingly
你就可以出去，我们还给你50万美元.
you walk out of here, we give you half a million dollars.
如果你没让他相信，我就把你扔出去
If you don't do it convincingly, I take you out back
用拖拉机碾过你的头，清楚了吗?
and I run my fucking tractor over your head. Okay?
明白吗?
Do you get that?
打电话.
Call them.
冷静.
Calm down.
是我Gregor.
It's Gregor.
我弄错了.
I was wrong.
不是他们.
It wasn't them.
我看得很清楚.
I got a good look.
我们会继续观察的.
We'll keep looking.
干得不错.
Nicely done.
听着，如果我们让他走...
Listen, if we let him go, then...
上帝，你说得不错.
Yeah, you're right.
上帝! 萨拉!
Jesus Christ! Sarah!
萨拉, 不是你想的那样.
Sarah, it's not what you think.
我们杀他是因为他要杀我们，我们是自卫!
We killed him because he was going to kill us. It was self defence!
别碰我!
Don't touch me!
我要带马修离开你.
I'm taking Matthew and we're leaving.
萨拉.
Sarah.
- 找到他了? - 是的.
- Have you got him? - Yes.
把车开过来，我要去追另一个家伙.
Grab the trunk, I'll get the other guy.
关于南美的话，看来你是错的.
I guess you were wrong about South America.
上帝!
Jesus!
可怜的李维斯,但他不用整容了.
Poor Reeves, he won't be getting plastic surgery after all.
不帮我吗?
Will you help me?
你抬这条腿.
You take his feet.
1，2，3...
One, two, three...
把他的腿放下来.
Put his feet way down.
来啊.
Come on.
Luigi, 是我汤姆 瑞普利.
Hey, Luigi, it's Tom Ripley.
你好吗?
How are you?
你店里有牡丹花吗?
Do you happen to have any Chinese tree peonies in the shop?
真美，红的还是粉红?
Lovely. Pink or red?
棒极了，我喜欢红色，听着 Louisa今晚的音乐会，
Terrific, I like the red. Listen, Louisa's concert tonight
是在Teatro Olimpico.
is at Teatro Olimpico.
您能送去4，5打吗？ 我来开车.
Could we send over four, five dozen if you have it? I'll drive.
太好了，谢谢.
Lovely. Thank you much.
哦，他怎么样?
Ah, yeah? How is he?
太好了，向他问好. 再次感谢，再见.
Give him my best. Thanks again. Bye.
你知道做坏事最有趣的是什么吗?
Know the most interesting thing about doing something terrible?
什么?
What?
经常是，过了几天，就都不记得了.
Often after a few days you can't even remember it.
让我感觉非常，非常好.
That makes me feel really, really good.
- 你剩余部分的钱. - 不...
- The rest of your money. - No...
根据我和李维斯的安排. 这是你的.
As per my arrangement with Reeves. It's yours.
我不能确定这一切都是为了钱.
I'm not sure all this was about the money.
我很怀疑，毕竟我们都是文明人.
You know what, I doubt it. After all we're two civilised people.
现在你已经不是全欧洲杀手最想杀的人了.
Now you're officially off Europe's active hit list.
- 谢谢. - 好了?
- Thank you. - Okay?
- 你妻子的事，祝你好运. - 谢谢.
- Good luck with the wife. - Thanks.
- 保重. - 你也是.
- Take care of yourself. - You too.
- 乔纳森. - 安静，要不我杀了你.
- Jonathan. - Quiet or I'll kill you.
你的朋友瑞普利在哪儿?
Where's your friend Ripley?
放开她! 别伤害她!
Let her go! Don't hurt her!
- 是我! - 谁带你们来的?
- It was me! - Who brought you here?
我自己来的.
I did it on my own.
..杀了她!
..kill her!
别伤害她!
Don't hurt her!
- 乔纳森! - 你为什么要这么做?
- Jonathan! - Why did you do that?
不，求你.
No, please.
萨拉, 一会儿我们要打电话给警察.
Sarah, in a few minutes we'll have to call the police.
告诉他们这里有入室抢劫.
Tell them there was a burglary.
你丈夫回来了，有一番打斗和交火.
Your husband came home, there was a struggle and there were shots.
你昏过去了, 就记得这些.
You're in shock, that's all you remember.
听着...
Listen...
..拿着这个，这是他剩余部分的报酬.
..take this. It's the balance of his payment.
他挣来的.
He earned it.
如果你需要...
If you need...
好吧，我没打算会得到感谢.
It's okay. I didn't expect thanks.